In the year 845,
the Colossal Titan and the
Armored Titan suddenly appeared
and destroyed one of humanity's walls..
and everyday life with it.
Humanity abandoned Wall Maria,
lost 20% of its population and
one-third of its territory,
and was forced to retreat behind Wall Rose.
In the year 850,
the Colossal Titan reappeared
and demolished another wall.
Once again, humanity allowed the
Titans to further their advance.
One after another, soldiers fell to the Titans.
And then...
Eren!
Hurry!
Eren Jaeger, who had fallen prey to one...
...reappeared from inside a mysterious Titan.
Attention!
Dot Pyxis, the top officer in charge
of the entire southern territory,
took notice of Eren Jaeger's
strength while fighting in Titan form
and decided to carry out an unusual plan.
In Titan form,
he will lift that giant rock,
carry it to the wrecked gate,
and seal the hole!
Should this operation succeed,
humanity will have taken back land
from the Titans for the very first time!
For us, that single, small step...
...will be a great leap forward!
However, that plan was on the
verge of failure as soon as it began...
Unknown are the names
of the flowers that have been trampled
Birds have fallen to the earth
and long for the wind
Prayers won't solve anything
Only the will to fight
can change the here and now!
O pigs who laugh at the resolve
to walk over corpses to move forward
Livestock complacency? False prosperity?
Give us the freedom of dying,
starving wolves!
The humiliation of being caged
is what triggers us to fight back
We hunters slaughter prey
beyond the castle walls,
consumed with surging bloodlust,
as our crimson bows and arrows
pierce scarlet holes into the twilight
Wound: The Struggle for Trost, Part 8
We've successfully managed to gather
most of the Titans
into the corner of the city,
yet, despite avoiding
combat as much as possible,
around 20% of our soldiers have been lost.
No, they were not "lost."
The soldiers did not
die of their own accord.
I ordered them to their deaths.
Humanity is now perched on
the brink of extinction.
If it means ensuring humankind's survival,
I'm willing to go down
in history as a butcher.
Ackermann!
Hey! Stop, Ackermann!
Get away from him!
Eren! Don't you recognize me?!
I'm Mikasa!
Part of your family!
You have to seal the hole with that rock!
The operation's a failure.
I knew there was no "secret weapon."
Eren! You're human!
You're..!
Dodge, Ackermann!
What the hell?!
He's just a regular, dumb Titan!
- Eren!
- Captain Ian!
Two Titans approaching from ahead!
A 10-meter one and a 6-meter one!
One 12-meter Titan is closing in from the rear!
Ian! We have to withdraw!
There's no way that kid's sealing the hole!
Agreed. We have no
choice but to leave him here.
Red smoke shell from the Elite Squad!
It seems the mission to seal
the hole has hit a serious snag.
For nothing...!
Our friends...
have died for nothing!
Hey, look over there!
What is it?! What's wrong?!
They've... failed?
How?
Hey! Where are you going, Armin?!
Commander Pyxis.
We should go back to
defending the gate immediately.
Just give the word, Sir.
No.
Shall I order the
Elite Squad to withdraw?
No.
Continue to lure the
Titans into the corner of town.
As for the Elite Squad, I've left all
on-site decision-making in their hands.
They're more than just skilled.
They're the best of the best, with the
fate of humankind on their shoulders.
Admitting defeat so easily is not an option.
If we don't want our fallen
soldiers' deaths to be in vain...
...then we must struggle
for as long as we live.
Hey! This is no time
to hesitate! Make the call!
Ian! It isn't your fault!
This whole mission
was a long shot to begin with!
We all understand!
It was worth a shot,
and we did the best that we could!
So our teams are
going back up the wall now!
Wait!
Wait. Calm down, Ackermann...
Rico Team, take out
the 12-meter one to the rear!
Mitabi Team and my team
will deal with the two ahead!
What?!
I was the one put in charge!
Do as you're ordered!
We can't leave Jaeger defenseless!
Change of plans!
We're to defend Jaeger from the
other Titans until we can recover him!
He holds a precious chance for humanity.
We can't abandon him just like that!
Because unlike us, he can't be replaced.
Hundreds of people
have died in this mission alone
for that failure of a human weapon!
Yet you want to recover him and go
through this same thing all over again?!
That's right.
We have to keep trying,
no matter how many people die!
What happened with Eren?!
Armin's on his way there.
It'll be all right... I think.
You think?
I'm sure everything will be fine.
- Eren'll pull through for us!
- Yeah...
Gathering the Titans in the corner of town
seems nothing but pointless to me.
A fight against a Titan always
turns into a battle of attrition.
We need to avoid losing men
at this point in time.
Meaning soldiers who die at
"this point in time" are dying for nothing?
We'll wage war someday!
So it makes sense to minimize our
losses and conserve our manpower
until that time comes!
- This was the right call to make!
- Was it really, though?
It was!
Well, let's just try not
to end up being "losses."
Both of us.
Are you serious, Ian?!
How is humanity ever
going to beat the Titans then?!
Tell me, Rico!
What other way do we have of
putting an end to all this?!
How can we defeat the
overwhelming might of the Titans
while maintaining our humanity
and not letting anyone die?!
I have no idea how to
defeat the Titans, obviously.
Yes.
That's why we must do this now.
It's our only option.
We have to lay down
our lives and go down bravely
for this so-called human weapon
we barely know anything about!
It's pathetic, isn't it?
That this is all we humans can do...
So, what do you say?
This is our battle to wage.
Our chance to struggle!
I refuse.
Rico!
I'll follow your plan.
I think your assessment is right.
I'm going to struggle with all my might
and make them taste
the ferocity of humanity.
Because I refuse to die for nothing.
My team will handle
the 12-meter one to the rear.
Let's go! We have the two in front!
Yeah.
Thank you, Captain Ian.
There's no need to thank me, Ackermann.
I was scared stiff there, since there
was no telling what you might do next.
Now you can act freely,
as originally planned.
That should make
better use of your ability.
Yes, Sir.
This is to protect your lover, after all.
He's family...
Huh?
The damaged parts haven't repaired?
Is it because of his earlier wounds?
How is it affecting Eren?
In fact, what guarantee is there
that he can turn back to normal at all?
No, never mind.
I won't figure anything out just by thinking.
For now, I have to do what I can do!
Eren... Mikasa...
What happened?!
Huh?
What... am I doing now?
Am I sitting?
I can't see anything...
What day is today?
Where am I?
Oh...
I'm home...
I'm gonna sleep.
Eren...
What are you doing, Eren?!
Listen up!
We can't let any Titans leave
this corner of town, no matter what!
Focus on that and keep luring them!
You don't need to fight them! Is that clear?
You'll run along the ground,
three cadets per team.
When you reach the wall,
you leap back up.
Don't die out there.
If by some slim chance a
Titan goes astray, we'll take it out.
"By some slim chance?"
There's a pretty good chance, if you ask me.
If we sense any risk,
are we free to act on our own discretion?
If it'll help somehow.
Kirschtein Team, move out!
Yes, Sir!
Crap! Behind us!
One 13-meter Titan!
It's headed straight for Jaeger!
We have more Titans
coming through the gate!
Four of them, around ten meters high!
- Ackermann! You have the rear one!
- Understood!
Don't let it get to Jaeger!
- Let's hold 'em off here!
- Understood!
Elite soldiers or not, two teams
can't handle four Titans at once...
This can't be...
Why are there so many Titans
even though there are so few people here?
Wait, could it be that Eren
is drawing them in?!
Mikasa!
What happened to the plan?!
Armin!
What's happened to Eren?!
Get away! It's dangerous there!
That Titan isn't acting through Eren's will!
I called out to him,
but he wouldn't respond!
There's no getting through to him anymore!
What about the plan?!
It's failed!
We're fighting because
we can't leave Eren behind!
But there are too many Titans...
At this rate,
we'll eventually be wiped out!
From the back of the
head to the nape of the neck...
...one meter high and ten centimeters across!
Armin!
I'll get Eren out of here!
You just protect us from the other Titans!
Huh? What are you...?
Eren came out of the Titans' vital spot!
My guess is that has something to do
with whatever makes the Titans tick.
It's okay...
As long as I miss the center...
...he won't die.
It'll just...
...hurt a little bit!
Armin!
Stop, Armin! That's too reckless!
Mikasa!
Just go do what you can!
There are lives you can help save!
Leave Eren to me and go!
Eren! Can you hear me?!
Pull yourself together!
We're all going to die
if you don't come out of there!
Don't give in to the Titan's body!
Now just hurry and
get out of this lump of flesh!
Get out of here?
Why?
I'm sleepy now...
Eren!
Come out! Hurry!
Eren! Eren!
What happened to avenging your mother?!
You were gonna drive
out all the Titans, remember?!
You hate them for killing
your mother, remember?!
What are you talking about, Armin?
My mom's right here...
Eren! Eren!
Wake up, Eren!
You're in there, aren't you?! Eren!
If we stay here, the Titans will kill us!
It'll all end here!
Seriously, you're not making any sense, Armin...
Why should I have to go outside?
Yeah...
Why would I want to leave?
Why would I want to join the Scouts...?
Like it or not, we're on our own now!
Go'! you!
About time you kicked the bucket, bastard!
Make distance for now!
I've returned!
I'll rendezvous with Mitabi Team!
Huh?!
Jean!
Get going!
I've had enough of
people dying because of me!
Damn! Of all the times to have a malfunction!
Jean!
What's going on?
Why isn't he using his ODM gear?!
Oh no!
Don't tell me it's malfunctioning?!
I'll manage somehow!
Damn... I can't believe
I'm draggin' everyone down...
Will this really work out somehow?
Eren...
We're supposed to explore the
outside world someday, remember?
Far beyond these walls, there stretch
fiery waters, lands of ice,
and sandy snowfields...
The world my mom and
dad planned to venture into.
I figured you'd just forgotten,
but you actually stopped talking about it
because you didn't want
me to join the Scouts, huh?
The outside... world...?
Eren... Answer me...
Even though just one step
outside the wall lies a hellish world...
And even though it might mean
dying a gruesome death like my parents...
Why did you want to
venture into the outside world?!
Why?
Isn't that obvious?
Because...
...I was born in this world!
Your dreams are where your heart is
They're more fragile than life itself
Over and over you cast them aside,
only to find more
Now, rest in peace
Pounding impulses defile the things we wish for
and the more we forget
the more we remember again
In this beautiful, cruel world
all I can do is ask why we're still alive
Oh, with our strength... and our weakness...
what are we going to protect if there's no sense
to anything anymore?
Go! Run! Live!
As innumerable words mix and
countless lives are lost on the battlefield,
Eren holds hope aloft and heads for the gate.
Primal Desire: The Struggle for Trost, Part 9